<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: plugins | Prashanth Babu]]></title>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/categories/plugins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-21T23:30:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://p7h.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prashanth Babu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse Plugins]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="post">
<div style="font-family: Roboto; font-size: 15px; white-space: normal;"><div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Eclipse</a> was my main IDE for all my JavaEE and Web development all the time in my career. For all plain Java development and Android app development, I used to revert to <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a> Community Edition, which allows only plain Java development and not Enterprise Java development i.e. JavaEE or Web Development [Spring, Hibernate, Grails, etc]. For more info on what is allowed and what is not allowed in Community Edition, please refer&nbsp;<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/editions_comparison_matrix.html" target="_blank">this matrix</a>&nbsp;on JetBrains website. Post the <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/jetbrains-mayan-doomsday-special-offers.html" target="_blank">Mayan Doomsday Offer</a> by JetBrains, thanks to the 75% steep discount on 20th December, I now have IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Edition as well.</div><!--more--><div style="text-align: justify;"><br />Eclipse is open source and is free to use. It is a thriving community for individuals and organizations which collaborate on commercially-friendly open source software. So, over a period of time Eclipse grew on all developers and almost everyone uses it as their main driver for development. And what&#8217;s more with Scala, Groovy and Android teams giving support for Eclipse as the first IDE has given it a good momentum in the past few years.&nbsp;The plugin ecosystem is huge in Eclipse and in fact, these plugins have helped Eclipse grow as a platform what it is today.&nbsp;Such is the popularity of plugins in Eclipse ecosystem that they have also launched <a href="http://marketplace.eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Marketplace</a> for Eclipse plugins. If something is missing in Eclipse, don&#8217;t worry, just check the Marketplace for the plugin or else you can develop a plugin in no time actually. That has been the mindset of a lot of Java developers in Eclipse ecosystem. There are thousands of plugins available for Eclipse right from customizing the IDE to Maven integration to Python IDE to Spring IDE, for Checkstyle, PMD, FindBugs, etc.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">With all my prior experience in using Eclipse, I have some goto plugins which I install the moment I get a brand new Eclipse version.&nbsp;Here is the list of all Eclipse plugins which I have used till now with a short description and the Eclipse Update Sites of the plugin.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><script src="https://gist.github.com/4389668.js"></script>Hope this was of some help to you.</div><br />Also, if you are interested in IntelliJ IDEA plugins, please check my <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/intellij-ide-plugins.html" target="_blank">earlier post</a>&nbsp;which lists down all the IDEA plugins which I use.</div></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packages in Sublime Text]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/11/packages-in-sublime-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/11/packages-in-sublime-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If I am not working on Eclipse or IntelliJ IDEA, I will be grokking on <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank">Sublime Text</a>. Its a wonderful text editor and in fact it’s more than a text editor. Unlimited trial period, multiple cursors, easy customization are its main USPs.<br /></p>

<p>There are a number of blogposts which explain why / how Sublime Text is good. Two of them are from NetTuts. Follow them and see how simple and easy it is to configure and personalize Sublime as per your requirements:
<!--more--></p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/tools-and-tips/sublime-text-2-tips-and-tricks/" target="_blank">Sublime Text 2 Tips and Tricks</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://tutsplus.com/course/improve-workflow-in-sublime-text-2/" target="_blank">Perfect Workflow in Sublime Text 2</a></li>
</ul>

<p>If you have followed the above articles, you would know that the first thing you do after installing Sublime Text is, install <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control" target="_blank">Package Control</a> and its all simple from there to install other packages.<br /></p>

<p>Following list has all the packages I have right now which are very useful for my work. First install Package Control and then search for the required packages [with the name listed here] in Package Control for installation, that’s all you have to do.
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4388830.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>Anaconda -- Turns ST3 into a full featured Python IDE.
Case Conversion -- Case conversion plugin (pascal, camel, snake) for ST3.
ColorPicker -- Color Picker plugin.
Highlight -- For exporting highlighted code as RTF or HTML.
Javatar -- Java Completions for ST3.
Package Control -- A comprehensive Package Manager for ST3.
Schemr -- To quickly change ST3 color scheme.
SideBarEnhancements -- Enhancements to ST3 Sidebar for files and folders.
SublimeREPL -- Run an interpreter inside ST3 (useful for Clojure, CoffeeScript, F#, Groovy, Haskell, Lua, MozRepl, NodeJS, Python, R, Ruby, Scala, shell, etc).
Terminal -- Launch terminals from the current file or the root project folder in ST3.
Theme - Flatland -- Minimal theme for ST3 [built on top of Theme - Soda].
Theme - Soda -- Dark and light custom UI Themes for ST3.
Theme - Soda SolarizedDark -- Dark and light custom UI Themes for ST3 [forked from Theme - Soda].
Themr -- To quickly change ST3 UI theme.

Misc:
Dayle Rees Color Schemes -- ST3 Themes by Dayle Rees.
Theme - Acqua -- ST3 theme to match the native OS X App Kit and ProKit themes.
Theme - Refined -- ST3 theme forked from the Acqua Theme.
Tomorrow Color Schemes -- Tomorrow Color Schemes for ST3.</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>In a future post, I will add User Settings of Sublime Text.<br /></p>

<p><em>EDIT</em>: I added another post on detailing <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/my-user-settings-of-sublime-text.html" target="_blank">my User Settings of Sublime Text</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
