<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: plugins | Prashanth Babu]]></title>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/categories/plugins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-10T13:44:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://p7h.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prashanth Babu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse Plugins]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Eclipse</a> was my main IDE for all my JavaEE and Web development all the time in my career. For all plain Java development and Android app development, I used to revert to <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a> Community Edition, which allows only plain Java development and not Enterprise Java development i.e. JavaEE or Web Development [Spring, Hibernate, Grails, etc]. For more info on what is allowed and what is not allowed in Community Edition, please check <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/editions_comparison_matrix.html" target="_blank">matrix on CE and Ultimate Editions</a>.<br />
Post the <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/jetbrains-mayan-doomsday-special-offers.html" target="_blank">Mayan Doomsday Offer</a> by JetBrains, thanks to the 75% steep discount on 20th December, 2012 I now have IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Edition as well <em>and have been renewing every year after that</em>.<br />
<!--more--></p>

<p>Eclipse is open source and is free to use. It is a thriving community for individuals and organizations which collaborate on commercially-friendly open source software. So, over a period of time Eclipse grew on all developers and almost everyone uses it as their main driver for development. And what’s more with Scala, Groovy and Android teams giving support for Eclipse as the first IDE has given it a good momentum in the past few years.<br /></p>

<p>The plugin ecosystem is huge in Eclipse and in fact, these plugins have helped Eclipse grow as a platform what it is today. Such is the popularity of plugins in Eclipse ecosystem that they have also launched <a href="http://marketplace.eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Marketplace</a> for Eclipse plugins. If something is missing in Eclipse, don’t worry, just check the Marketplace for the plugin or else you can develop a plugin in no time actually. That has been the mindset of a lot of Java developers in Eclipse ecosystem. There are thousands of plugins available for Eclipse right from customizing the IDE to Maven integration to Python IDE to Spring IDE, for Checkstyle, PMD, FindBugs, etc. <br /></p>

<p>With all my prior experience in using Eclipse, I have some goto plugins which I install the moment I get a brand new Eclipse version. Here is the list of all Eclipse plugins which I have used till now with a short description and the Eclipse Update Sites of the plugin.
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4389668.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>AnyEdit: Adds several new tools to the context menu of text-based Eclipse editors, to output consoles, to Eclipse main menu and editor toolbar -- http://andrei.gmxhome.de/eclipse
Code Recommenders: Intelligent code completion -- http://download.eclipse.org/recommenders/updates/stable/e42/
EasyShell: Opens shell window, runs selected file in the shell; opens explorer window (or nautilus / konqueror) and copies path -- http://pluginbox.sourceforge.net
Eclipse Color Themes: Variety of Color Themes for Eclipse -- http://eclipse-color-theme.github.com/update
EditBox: For highlighting the background of the source code -- http://editbox.sourceforge.net/updates
FindBugs: For static analysis to look for bugs in Java code  -- http://findbugs.cs.umd.edu/eclipse
Google CodePro AnalytiX: For improving software quality and reducing developments costs and schedules -- http://dl.google.com/eclipse/inst/codepro/latest/3.7
MouseFeed: For learning keyboard shortcuts in Eclipse -- http://update.mousefeed.com
SnipMatch: Code snippet search tool for Eclipse -- http://languageinterfaces.com/eclipsePlugin</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Hope this was of some help to you.<br />
Also, if you are interested in IntelliJ IDEA plugins, please check my <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/intellij-ide-plugins.html" target="_blank">earlier post</a> which lists all the IntelliJ IDEA plugins I use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packages in Sublime Text]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/11/packages-in-sublime-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/11/packages-in-sublime-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If I am not working on Eclipse or IntelliJ IDEA, I will be grokking on <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank">Sublime Text</a>. Its a wonderful text editor and in fact it’s more than a text editor. Unlimited trial period, multiple cursors, easy customization are its main USPs.<br /></p>

<p>There are a number of blogposts which explain why / how Sublime Text is good. Two of them are from NetTuts. Follow them and see how simple and easy it is to configure and personalize Sublime as per your requirements:
<!--more--></p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/tools-and-tips/sublime-text-2-tips-and-tricks/" target="_blank">Sublime Text 2 Tips and Tricks</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://tutsplus.com/course/improve-workflow-in-sublime-text-2/" target="_blank">Perfect Workflow in Sublime Text 2</a></li>
</ul>

<p>If you have followed the above articles, you would know that the first thing you do after installing Sublime Text is, install <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control" target="_blank">Package Control</a> and its all simple from there to install other packages.<br /></p>

<p>Following list has all the packages I have right now which are very useful for my work. First install Package Control and then search for the required packages [with the name listed here] in Package Control for installation, that’s all you have to do.
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4388830.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>Anaconda -- Turns ST into a full featured Python IDE.
Case Conversion -- Case conversion plugin (pascal, camel, snake).
ColorPicker -- Color Picker plugin.
DocBlockr -- Simplifies writing DocBlock comments in various languages.
Golang Build -- Official Sublime Text package for Go build system integration.
GoSublime -- Golang plugin collection.
Javatar -- Java Completions.
Markdown Preview -- Markdown Preview.
Package Control -- A comprehensive Package Manager.
PlainTasks -- ToDo list plugin.
Pretty JSON -- Prettify JSON.
Revert All Files -- To revert all unsaved files to their last saved state.
Scala Syntax -- Syntax file for Scala.
ScalaFormat -- Scala code formatter.
ScalaWorksheet -- Worksheet functionality for Scala.
Schemr -- To quickly change color scheme.
SideBarEnhancements -- Enhancements to Sidebar for files and folders.
SublimeHighlight -- For exporting highlighted code as RTF or HTML.
SublimeREPL -- Run an interpreter inside ST (useful for Clojure, CoffeeScript, F#, Groovy, Haskell, Lua, MozRepl, NodeJS, Python, R, Ruby, Scala, shell, etc).
Tabright -- To create new tabs on the right.
Terminal -- Launch terminals from the current file or the root project folder in ST.
Theme - Flatland -- Minimal theme for ST [built on top of Theme - Soda].
Theme - Soda -- Dark and light custom UI Themes for ST.
Theme - Soda SolarizedDark -- Dark and light custom UI Themes for ST [forked from Theme - Soda].
Themr -- To quickly change ST UI theme.

Misc:
Dayle Rees Color Schemes -- ST Themes by Dayle Rees.
Theme - Acqua -- ST theme to match the native OS X App Kit and ProKit themes.
Theme - Refined -- ST theme forked from the Acqua Theme.
Tomorrow Color Schemes -- Tomorrow Color Schemes for ST.</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>In a future post, I will add User Settings of Sublime Text.<br /></p>

<p><em>EDIT</em>: I added another post on detailing <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/my-user-settings-of-sublime-text.html" target="_blank">my User Settings of Sublime Text</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
