<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: misc | Prashanth Babu]]></title>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-27T23:02:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://p7h.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prashanth Babu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Blogger to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/18/migration-blogger-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-18T16:31:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/18/migration-blogger-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So like many others in the blogging world, I too shifted from Blogger to statically generated Octopress hosted on GitHub last week.And today I completed migrating all my <a href="http://P7h.blogspot.com">Blogger</a> posts to <a href="http://P7h.org">Octopress</a> and got them hosted here. Henceforth will leave Blogger as-is and will try to make this as my active blog.<br /></p>

<p>Initially I was kinda apprehensive that I might have to put in significant effort to migrate my posts from Blogger to Octopress. But it turned out to be very simple actually. In fact, it was as simple as running just a single Ruby script.
<!--more--></p>

<p>I have listed below the required steps for migration, just in case if someone needs a ready reference.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Export your content from Blogger:<br />
    <ul>
      <li>Go to Blogger Settings -&gt; Other -&gt; Blog Tools -&gt; Click on “Export blog” link.<br /></li>
      <li>This screenshot might be helpful for reaching this section in Blogger maze.<br />
  <img src="/assets/images/Blogger_Export_Posts.png" alt="" /></li>
      <li>This downloads an xml file [in the format blog-<em>month</em>-<em>date</em>-<em>year</em>.xml] with all the content from your blogs. In my case, it turned out to be “blog-01-18-2015.xml”.<br /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Ruby script for migration:<br />
    <ul>
      <li>Then get a copy of a Ruby script from this <a href="https://gist.github.com/P7h/6df39591aa5554f4335c" target="_blank">Gist</a> for converting posts from Blogger format to Octopress compatible format.<br /></li>
      <li>Please remember you might need to have nokogiri gem - if not already installed - before moving further. Command to install this gem is: <code>gem install nokogiri</code>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Execution of Ruby script:<br />
    <ul>
      <li>Run this Ruby script on the xml file you downloaded above. Command for execution is: <code>ruby import.rb blog-01-18-2015.xml</code>.<br /></li>
      <li>This generates the content of your blog in html files.<br /></li>
      <li>During the migration, this script tries to retain the exact same path you would have used in the Blogger script and also tries to get the date [but not time] of the post and categories, etc you would have listed for each of your posts in Blogger. Very neat I would say.<br /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Post generation of posts:<br />
    <ul>
      <li>Copy the generated html files to <code>_source/posts</code> folder in your Octopress folder and you are done.<br /></li>
      <li>Do a <code>rake generate</code> and <code>rake preview</code> and check the blog posts have all come well and confirm if the migration went fine.<br /></li>
      <li>Once you are happy with the migration and content, perform <code>rake deploy</code>.</li>
      <li>And don’t forget to push these changes to GitHub.<br /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Few caveats:<br />
    <ul>
      <li>Please note that all the files usually crated by rake tasks are .md i.e. markdown files while the migrated scripts will be plain html files.<br /></li>
      <li>Also please note that post the migration, all the migrated posts will retain the correct date, but time gets defaulted to 12:00 AM. I could not find time to debug the issue though.<br /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Hope these steps were useful to you. Enjoy the new blog and glory!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress blogging setup on a new machine]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/16/octopress-setup-windows/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-16T14:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/16/octopress-setup-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post gives a brief intro to setting up Octopress blog on a new Windows machine. This assumes you already have your blogs on your GitHub account and are changing the machine or setting up on a new machine.</p>

<h3 id="step-1-install-ruby-v193">Step 1: Install Ruby v1.9.3</h3>

<p>Download and install Ruby v1.9.3 from <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads/">here</a>. <code>ruby --version</code> should give something on the lines of <code>ruby 1.9.3p551 (2014-11-13) [i386-mingw32]</code>.
<!--more--></p>

<h3 id="step-2-install-rubydevkit">Step 2: Install RubyDevKit</h3>

<p>Download and install Ruby Dev Kit from <a href="https://github.com/downloads/oneclick/rubyinstaller/DevKit-tdm-32-4.5.2-20111229-1559-sfx.exe">here</a></p>

<p>Change the directory to folder where you installed RubyDevKit and then run the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>cd RubyDevKit
ruby dk.rb init
ruby dk.rb install
</code></pre>

<h3 id="step-3-clone-your-repo-and-install-dependencies">Step 3: Clone your repo and install dependencies</h3>

<p>Clone your repository preferably using GitHub client for Windows. Please note you must point to <code>source</code> and not <code>master</code> of your GitHub repo.</p>

<p>Change directory to that folder [in this case, I am referring to my folder as an example; you must change to your appropriate folder] and run the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
gem install bundler
bundle install
</code></pre>

<h4 id="step-3a-if-you-get-ssl-errors-from-running-the-above-commands">Step 3a: If you get SSL errors from running the above commands</h4>

<p>If the above commands fail, <a href="https://gist.github.com/P7h/fcb67d22aad7f9eee6e7">manually add trust certificate to Rubygems</a> and then retry to install the dependencies with the above commands.</p>

<h3 id="step-4-setup-the-github-pages-and-generate-and-preview-the-blog">Step 4: Setup the GitHub pages and generate and preview the blog</h3>

<p>Run the following commands to complete the blog setup. With preview you can view your blog on your machine on port <a href="http://localhost:4000">4000</a>:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
rake setup_github_pages
rake generate
rake preview
</code></pre>

<h3 id="step-5-github-personal-access-token">Step 5: GitHub Personal Access Token</h3>
<p>If you have enabled 2 FA on GitHub, you must get GitHub access token from <a href="https://github.com/settings/applications">applications</a> page on GitHub. You need to give this access token for user name while performing <code>git commit</code> or <code>rake deploy</code> or <code>rake gen_deploy</code> in the next steps.</p>

<h3 id="step-6-deploy-the-blog">Step 6: Deploy the blog</h3>
<p>Once you are done with all your changes, deploy your changes to your blog by running these commands:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
rake generate
rake deploy
</code></pre>

<p>Or generate and deploy both together with a single command:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
rake gen_deploy
</code></pre>

<h3 id="step-7-commit-your-changes">Step 7: Commit your changes</h3>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
git add -A
git commit -m 'commit message'
git push origin source
</code></pre>

<h3 id="step-8-other-useful-commands">Step 8: Other useful commands</h3>
<p>For creating a new page:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
rake new_page["new page"]
</code></pre>

<p>For creating a new post:</p>

<pre><code>cd p7h.github.com
rake new_post["new post"]
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/12/a-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T00:12:46+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2015/01/12/a-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first blogpost using Octopress and GitHub.</p>

<p>Previously, I had my blogs hosted on <a href="http://P7h.blogspot.com">Blogger</a>.
Though Blogger engine is good, I could never spend time to create a template on my own to make my blogpage look good and on top of that the default templates and layouting always made go crazy since its too tedious to spend time on fine-tuning and make the page look zazzy. 
<!--more-->
Being a minimalist, I would like to go with minimum cruft and more emphasis on the code and content rather than the styling of the blogpage with an attractive UI.</p>

<p>So here I am, trying to use Octopress and trying to generate static pages using GitHub. I went with default Octopress template. Setting it up on Windows with Ruby was a bit painful initially and I went helter-skelter looking for help mostly with Google and SO. But after 2 trials, I was able to get my default website up and running. I hope this will be a nice experience with just markdown and code-highlighting to the rescue.</p>

<p>Over a period of time or whenever I get time, I will be exporting all my posts from Blogger to GitHub hosted static pages. Though its a considerable effort, I would like to give it a shot and move away from Blogger and maintain this as my primary blogpage.</p>

<p>For now, just “Hello World”. :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz Memorial at New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2013/01/20/aaron-swartz-memorial/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2013/01/20/aaron-swartz-memorial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aaron Swartz, a very accomplished and a highly talented nerd committed suicide last Friday, i.e. 11th January, 2013 at an young age of 26 years. So many people have written so much about him. Check the complete <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz">Wikipedia</a> page and check the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz#References" target="_blank">References</a> section of his Wikipedia page for more info and other articles written by his friends. He has left wonderful impressions on Reddit, Creative Commons, SOPA, Markdown, RSS, web.py to name a few of his outstanding contributions.<br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/quinn/870253651/" target="_blank" title="Aaron by quinnums, on Flickr"><img alt="Aaron Swartz" height="500" src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1150/870253651_9b076ba1b3.jpg" width="500" /></a></div>
<!--more-->

<p>Aaron’s <a href="http://www.rememberaaronsw.com/">memorial</a> was held on Saturday, 19th January, 2013 at Cooper Union, New York. Here is the complete set of recorded videos from his memorial which are hosted on <a href="http://www.livestream.com/democracynow/folder?dirId=0545b862-1026-4b88-86ff-409745806958">livestream</a>. There are totally 6 videos which you must checkout to understand what are his contributions and how talented a person he was and what impressions he has left people with, even such an young age.<br /></p>

<p>If you are hard-pressed for time, then ensure you at least check the message from Taren Stinebrickner-Kauffman, partner of Aaron, embedded below. It is really inspiring.<br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="385" scrolling="no" src="http://cdn.livestream.com/embed/democracynow?layout=4&amp;clip=pla_f83c80fe-0fc0-474c-9936-efe8659466f6&amp;color=0xe7e7e7&amp;autoPlay=false&amp;mute=false&amp;iconColorOver=0x888888&amp;iconColor=0x777777&amp;allowchat=true&amp;height=385&amp;width=640" style="border: 0; outline: 0;" width="640"></iframe><br />

Rest in peace Aaron!!
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Knight Rises ultimate trilogy trailer]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/the-dark-knight-rises-ultimate-trilogy/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/the-dark-knight-rises-ultimate-trilogy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wonderfully put together ultimate trilogy trailer of “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dark_Knight_Rises" target="_blank">The Dark Knight Rises</a>”, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Nolan" target="_blank">Christopher Nolan</a>’s Batman series. Christopher Nolan’s taking is brilliant as always. Apart from him, Hans Zimmer’s background score is excellent. I concur with the comment in the below Youtube page which says: “Without Hans Zimmer this trilogy wouldn’t be nearly as epic as it is”. If you have any doubts, you should check out the Original Motion Picture Soundtrack of <i>The Dark Knight Rises</i> on <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Dark-Knight-Rises-Soundtrack/dp/B008645YEE" target="_blank">Amazon</a> or <a href="http://www.flipkart.com/dark-knight-rises/p/itmdbvq7g22yjmks?pid=DGADBVQ7WC4RGX8C" target="_blank">Flipkart</a>.<br /></p>

<p>The only thing I missed in this trailer is the voice of Bane i.e. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Hardy" target="_blank">Tom Hardy</a>. </p>

<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1T__uN5xmC0" width="800"></iframe>

<p><br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
