<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ide | Prashanth Babu]]></title>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/categories/ide/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://p7h.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-25T22:50:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://p7h.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prashanth Babu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse startup options or JVM Settings]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/29/eclipse-startup-options-or-jvm-settings/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/29/eclipse-startup-options-or-jvm-settings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In continuation to my other post on <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/intellij-idea-tuning-parameters.html" target="_blank">tuning IntelliJ IDEA</a>, in this post I am detailing the startup options [which are also called JVM Settings] for Eclipse IDE. Eclipse startup is controlled by the options in <code>eclipse.ini</code> file present directly under Eclipse installation folder [i.e. $ECLIPSE_HOME]. By default, Eclipse comes with a set of values in this file. But those values are not optimized and might cause issues and / or hangs in large projects which might have considerably bigger codebase. These can be tuned further for better performance.<br /></p>

<p>My startup options in my current version of Eclipse Juno i.e. v4.2.1 are listed below.
<!--more--></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4392224.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>-startup
plugins/org.eclipse.equinox.launcher_1.3.0.v20120522-1813.jar
--launcher.library
plugins/org.eclipse.equinox.launcher.win32.win32.x86_64_1.1.200.v20120522-1813
-vm
C:/Warez/Java/JDK7.0_10/jre/bin/server/jvm.dll
-showsplash
org.eclipse.platform
--launcher.XXMaxPermSize
256m
--launcher.defaultAction
openFile
-product
org.eclipse.epp.package.jee.product
--launcher.defaultAction
openFile
--launcher.XXMaxPermSize
256M
-vmargs
-server
-Declipse.p2.unsignedPolicy=allow
-Xms1024m
-Xmx1024m
-Xmn128m
-Xss4m
-XX:PermSize=256m
-XX:MaxPermSize=256m
-XX:+UseG1GC
-XX:+UseParallelGC
-Xverify:none
-XX:+UseFastAccessorMethods
-Dosgi.requiredJavaVersion=1.5
-Dhelp.lucene.tokenizer=standard</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Please use these options as a reference and update <code>eclipse.ini</code> file [please do take a backup of this file prior to updating it]. Also, one more important point to note is, use the latest <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index-jsp-138363.html" target="_blank">Sun / Oracle JDK</a> for starting Eclipse. This also has a profound effect on the Eclipse startup time as well as the IDE functionality with a decent sized codebase.<br /></p>

<p>Finally, in case you were looking for tuning the startup options of IntelliJ IDEA, please refer my earlier post on tuning <a href="http://p7h.org/2012/12/intellij-idea-tuning-parameters.html" target="_blank">startup parameters for IDEA</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse Plugins]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/27/eclipse-plugins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Eclipse</a> was my main IDE for all my JavaEE and Web development all the time in my career. For all plain Java development and Android app development, I used to revert to <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a> Community Edition, which allows only plain Java development and not Enterprise Java development i.e. JavaEE or Web Development [Spring, Hibernate, Grails, etc]. For more info on what is allowed and what is not allowed in Community Edition, please check <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/features/editions_comparison_matrix.html" target="_blank">matrix on CE and Ultimate Editions</a>.<br />
Post the <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/jetbrains-mayan-doomsday-special-offers.html" target="_blank">Mayan Doomsday Offer</a> by JetBrains, thanks to the 75% steep discount on 20th December, 2012 I now have IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Edition as well <em>and have been renewing every year after that</em>.<br />
<!--more--></p>

<p>Eclipse is open source and is free to use. It is a thriving community for individuals and organizations which collaborate on commercially-friendly open source software. So, over a period of time Eclipse grew on all developers and almost everyone uses it as their main driver for development. And what’s more with Scala, Groovy and Android teams giving support for Eclipse as the first IDE has given it a good momentum in the past few years.<br /></p>

<p>The plugin ecosystem is huge in Eclipse and in fact, these plugins have helped Eclipse grow as a platform what it is today. Such is the popularity of plugins in Eclipse ecosystem that they have also launched <a href="http://marketplace.eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Marketplace</a> for Eclipse plugins. If something is missing in Eclipse, don’t worry, just check the Marketplace for the plugin or else you can develop a plugin in no time actually. That has been the mindset of a lot of Java developers in Eclipse ecosystem. There are thousands of plugins available for Eclipse right from customizing the IDE to Maven integration to Python IDE to Spring IDE, for Checkstyle, PMD, FindBugs, etc. <br /></p>

<p>With all my prior experience in using Eclipse, I have some goto plugins which I install the moment I get a brand new Eclipse version. Here is the list of all Eclipse plugins which I have used till now with a short description and the Eclipse Update Sites of the plugin.
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4389668.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>AnyEdit: Adds several new tools to the context menu of text-based Eclipse editors, to output consoles, to Eclipse main menu and editor toolbar -- http://andrei.gmxhome.de/eclipse
Code Recommenders: Intelligent code completion -- http://download.eclipse.org/recommenders/updates/stable/e42/
EasyShell: Opens shell window, runs selected file in the shell; opens explorer window (or nautilus / konqueror) and copies path -- http://pluginbox.sourceforge.net
Eclipse Color Themes: Variety of Color Themes for Eclipse -- http://eclipse-color-theme.github.com/update
EditBox: For highlighting the background of the source code -- http://editbox.sourceforge.net/updates
FindBugs: For static analysis to look for bugs in Java code  -- http://findbugs.cs.umd.edu/eclipse
Google CodePro AnalytiX: For improving software quality and reducing developments costs and schedules -- http://dl.google.com/eclipse/inst/codepro/latest/3.7
MouseFeed: For learning keyboard shortcuts in Eclipse -- http://update.mousefeed.com
SnipMatch: Code snippet search tool for Eclipse -- http://languageinterfaces.com/eclipsePlugin</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Hope this was of some help to you.<br />
Also, if you are interested in IntelliJ IDEA plugins, please check my <a href="http://p7h.blogspot.com/2012/12/intellij-ide-plugins.html" target="_blank">earlier post</a> which lists all the IntelliJ IDEA plugins I use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guava toString() method generator for IntelliJ IDEA]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/22/guava-tostring-method-gen-for-intellij-idea/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/22/guava-tostring-method-gen-for-intellij-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a> comes bundled with <code>toString()</code> plugin. If you check the plugins in Settings, you should find GenerateToString plugin, which generates <code>toString()</code> method with options for String concat, StringBuffer, StringBuilder and ToStringBuilder (of Apache Commons) for generating this method.</p>

<p><a href="http://code.google.com/p/guava-libraries/" target="_blank">Google Guava</a> has even better helper method for generating <code>toString()</code> method for a JavaBean or POJO, which is both clutter free and has a very consistent format; in the form of <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Objects.html#toStringHelper(java.lang.Class)" target="_blank">Objects.toStringHelper(this)</a>. It looks more elegant than any of the above solutions, actually. Also, as I make it a point to use Google Guava in all my projects, I have defined the following template in my <code>toString()</code> method generator settings in IntelliJ IDEA.
<!--more--></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4388630.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>/**
 * Guava API toString() method generator for a JavaBean / POJO.
 * @return String representation of all the attributes of the bean.
 */
public String toString() {
    #set ($autoImportPackages = &quot;com.google.common.base.Objects&quot;)
    return Objects.toStringHelper(this)
    #foreach ($member in $members)
        .add(&quot;$member.name&quot;, $member.accessor)
    #end
        .toString();
}</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Follow the steps mentioned below for adding this template to your IntelliJ IDEA [picked up from <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/9445402" target="_blank">SO</a>]:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Go inside a Java Class in an editor in IntelliJ IDEA.</li>
  <li>Hit Alt + Insert to popup the “Generate” menu.</li>
  <li>Choose <code>toString()</code>.</li>
  <li>Click the “Settings” button.</li>
  <li>Go to the “Templates” tab.</li>
  <li>Create a new template named “Guava toString gen” (or any name you prefer).</li>
  <li>Add the above code to the template.</li>
</ol>

<p>Yes, its that simple!!  After configuring the above template, whenever you want to generate a <code>toString()</code> method for a Class, IntelliJ IDEA generates <code>toString()</code> using Guava template you have added just now.</p>

<p>Now, go ahead and give this a try and also check the other method <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Objects.ToStringHelper.html#omitNullValues()" target="_blank">omitNullValues()</a> which might be useful in some scenarios.</p>

<p>Also, as a bonus tip, Guava’s <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Objects.html" target="_blank">Objects</a> class also has 2 awesome helper methods which aide in writing readable <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Objects.html#equal(java.lang.Object, java.lang.Object)" target="_blank">equals()</a> and <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Objects.html#hashCode(java.lang.Object...)" target="_blank">hashcode()</a> methods. You should try them too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JetBrains Mayan Doomsday Special Offers ]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/20/jetbrains-mayan-doomsday-special-offers/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/20/jetbrains-mayan-doomsday-special-offers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JetBrains has an amazing set of IDEs right from Java to Python to Ruby and so on. They are a bit expensive though. For example, IntelliJ IDEA personal license can be bought for $199. But today, JetBrains is offering a steep discount of 75% on all their products which include <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/" target="_blank">PyCharm</a> and a host of <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/products.html" target="_blank">other awesome IDEs</a>.<br />
<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/specials/index.jsp" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img src="/assets/images/JetBrains_MayanDoomsday_Offer.png" alt="" /></a><br /></p>

<p>It is a limited period offer and to be precise its an offer only for 24 hours on 20<sup>th</sup> December, 2012. So, what are you waiting for? Head over to their website and NOW!!<br /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/specials/index.jsp" target="_blank">JetBrains Special Offer</a></p>

<p><em>EDIT: This offer expired on 21st December, 2012.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance Tuning of IntelliJ IDEA startup options]]></title>
    <link href="http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/10/intellij-idea-tuning-parameters/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://p7h.org/blog/2012/12/10/intellij-idea-tuning-parameters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/" target="_blank">IntelliJ IDEA</a> is my favorite IDE for all Java development related work. I do moonlight with Eclipse as well from time-to-time, but it is very less and also the sheer speed and power of IDEA pulls me back every time.</p>

<p>I have found the following tuning parameters to be effective for my day-to-day work for fast loading, caching, etc and for the IDE to function smoothly:
<!--more--></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4388881.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>-server
-Xms2048m
-Xmx2048m
-XX:NewSize=512m
-XX:MaxNewSize=512m
-XX:PermSize=512m
-XX:MaxPermSize=512m
-XX:+UseParNewGC
-XX:ParallelGCThreads=4
-XX:MaxTenuringThreshold=1
-XX:SurvivorRatio=8
-XX:+UseCodeCacheFlushing
-XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC
-XX:+AggressiveOpts
-XX:+CMSClassUnloadingEnabled
-XX:+CMSIncrementalMode
-XX:+CMSIncrementalPacing
-XX:+CMSParallelRemarkEnabled
-XX:CMSInitiatingOccupancyFraction=65
-XX:+CMSScavengeBeforeRemark
-XX:+UseCMSInitiatingOccupancyOnly
-XX:ReservedCodeCacheSize=64m
-XX:-TraceClassUnloading
-ea
-Dsun.io.useCanonCaches=false</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>If you are on 64-bit Windows OS, please add the above config in <em>idea64.exe.vmoptions</em> file and if 32-bit, please add these tuning parms to <em>idea.exe.vmoptions</em> present in IDEA_LOCATION/bin folder.<br /></p>

<p>Also just in case if you are not aware, on a 64-bit machine, if you want to launch IntelliJ IDEA in 64-bit mode, you need to launch <em>idea64.exe</em> and not <em>idea.exe</em>. For this, ensure you have <code>IDEA_JDK</code> and <code>IDEA_JDK_64</code> environment variables pointing to your 64-bit Java install folder.<br /></p>

<p>Finally, the above IntelliJ IDEA tuning parameters hold good for IntelliJ IDEA installed on a Linux machine as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
